Mss.B.St15
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, Nov. 2, 1857; 8x5; Porter, Thomas Conrad, 1822-1901
    Lancaster, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Mutilated. Friendly letter. Responds to Stauffer's proposal for book. Critiques drawings.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Mt. Joy, Nov. 8, 1857; 8x5; Smith, J. Jay, (John Jay), 1798-1881
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Mt. Joy, Nov. 27, 1857; 8x5; Moore, August O.
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Friendly letter. Concerning entomology. Sends list of books for sale.
  - Letter to [Jacob Stauffer], June, 1858; 7x4-1/2; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Concerning entomology. Refers to the academy of natural sciences.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Jan. 1, 1858; 10x8; Wickersham, James Pyle, 1825-1893
    Lancaster, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Refuses request.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Jan. 9, 1858; 8x5; Smith, J. Jay, (John Jay), 1798-1881
    Germantown, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, Jan. 27, 1858; 10x7-1/2; Morris, John G., (John Gottlieb), 1803-1895
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to G. W. Brewer, Feb. 3, 1858; 10x7-1/2; Brenneman, John H.
    Mt. Joy, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Enc. of request for aid from Stauffer. Recommends Stauffer.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Feb. 15, 1858; 7x4-1/2; Smith, J. Jay, (John Jay), 1798-1881
    Germantown, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning entomology. Business.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Feb. 19, 1858; 8x5; Smith, J. Jay, (John Jay), 1798-1881
    Germantown, A.L.S. 2p. Business. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Jacob Stauffer], March 2, 1858; 8-1/2x5; LeConte, John L., (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Concerning entomology.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Mt. Joy, March 7, 1858; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Mutilated, Concerning insects.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, April 9, 1858; 10x8; Smolnikar, Andrew B. (Andreas Bernardus), 1795-1869
    Shippensburg, A.L.S. 3p.and end. Concerning religion.
  - Recommendation of Jacob Stauffer, April 30, 1858; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Baldwin, Robert
    Harrisburg, D.S.: Robert Baldwin, et al. 1p. and end. Mutilated.
  - Letter to J[acob] R [sic] Stauffer, May 17, 1858; 8x5; Porter, Thomas Conrad, 1822-1901
    Lancaster, A.L.S. 2p.and end. Mutilated. Concerning botany. On same sheet is letter from A.F. Stauffer to J. Stauffer; May 25, 1858.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, May 25, 1858; 8-1/2x5; Smith, J. Jay, (John Jay), 1798-1881
    Germantown, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Friendly letter. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to [Jacob Stauffer], May 25, 1858; 8x5; Stauffer, Alfred F.
    A.L.S. 1p. Mutilated. Forwards letter from Porter. On same sheet as letter from Porter to Stauffer; May 17, 1858.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Mt. Joy, June 11, 1858; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning rodents.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Aug. 9, 1858; 10x8; Ongley, W. H.
    College Hill, A.L.S. 2p., end. Mutilated. Concerning an entomological publication
  - Letter to [Jacob Stauffer], Oct. 12, 1858; 8x5; LeConte, John L., (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end.and drawings of insects. Mutilated. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Nov. 10, 1858; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Smith, J. Jay, (John Jay), 1798-1881
  - Letter to [Jacob Stauffer], Dec. 8, 1858; 10x8; Cary, F. C.
    College Hill, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Mutilated. Friendly letter. Business.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Dec. 13, 1858; 7x4-1/2; Smith, J. Jay, (John Jay), 1798-1881
    Germantown, A.L.S. 2p.,end. Business.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, Dec. 22, 1858; 8-1/2x5; Moore, Daniel D. T.
    Rochester, A.L.S. 3p., end. Friendly letter. Business.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, [1858]; 7x4-1/2; Smith, J. Jay, (John Jay), 1798-1881
    Germantown A.L.S. 2p. Business.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Lancaster, Jan. 8, 1859; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, April 13, 1859; 7-1/2x8; Ongley, W. H.
    College Hill, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Business.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Aug. 6, 1859; 8x5; Spangler, A. M.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and enc.of prospectus for a farmer's magazine (1p.). Mutilated. Asks for an article for his proposed magazine.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Dec. 9, 1859; 10x7-1/2; Spangler, A. M.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Lancaster, Dec. 10, 1859; 10x7-1/2; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Joseph] Henry, Dec. 13, 1859; 10x8; Laurence, DeWitt C.
    Washington, L.S. Copy. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning Stauffer.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Feb. 4, 1860; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    Germantown, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Concerning natural history.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Feb. 13, 1860; 8x5; Hoopes, Josiah, 1832-1904
    West Chester, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning entomology.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Feb. 15, 1860; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Hoopes, Josiah, 1832-1904
    West Chester, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning entomology. Refers to Gray.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, June 5, 1860; 10x8; Spangler, A. M.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Mutilated. Business.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, June 30, 1860; 10x8; Spangler, A. M.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning a publication on insects.
  - Letter to [Jacob Stauffer], Oct. 11, 1860; 10x8; Greider, Rufus A.
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to [S. S.] Rathvon, Oct. 13, 1860; 10x8; Spangler, A. M.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Thanks him and Stauffer.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Dec. 5, 1860; 8x5; Saxton, Charles Maurice, 1812-1888
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Business.
  - Letter to [S. S.] Rathvon and [Jacob] Stauffer, Dec. 6, 1860; 10x8; Spangler, A. M.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Business.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, Feb. 12, 1861; 10x8; Beck, John
    A.L.S. 2p., end. Mutilated. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, June 26, 1861; 8x5; Wise, John, 1808-1879
    A.L.S. 1p. and end. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, July 2, 1861; 10x7-1/2; Houghton, J. S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, July 5, 1861; 10x8; Houghton, J. S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p., end. Mutilated. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, July 8, 1861; 10x8; Houghton, J. S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end.with sketches of insects. Mutilated. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, July 13, 1861; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Houghton, J. S.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Aug. 16, 1861; 10x8; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    Germantown, A.L.S. 2p., end. Mutilated. Business.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Oct. 19, 1861; 7-1/2x5-1/2; Houghton, J. S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Nov. 1, 1861; 7-1/2x5-1/2; Houghton, J. S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Nov. 8, 1861; 8x6-1/2; Houghton, J. S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Mutilated. Business.
  - Letter to J[acob] [Stauffer], Lancaster, Dec. 24, 1861; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Durand, Elias, 1794-1873
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning entomology.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, Dec. 30, 1861; 8x5-1/2; Moore, Daniel D. T.
    Rochester, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Friendly letter.
  - Report of committee on accounts of Jacob Stauffer., [1861]; 10x7-1/2; Historical, Agricultural and Mechanical institute of Lancaster
    D.S.: (signature mutilated) 1p. Mutilated.
  - Account with Jacob Stauffer, Jan. 29, 1862; 7x7-1/2; Rathvon, S. S., (Simon Snyder), 1812-1891
    Lancaster, A.D.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Lancaster, Feb. 15, 1862; 10-1/2x8; Durand, Elias, 1794-1873
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning insects. Refers to Le Conte.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Lancaster, Feb. 22, 1862; 8x5; Norton, Edward
    Farmington, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Concerning hornets. Refers to Baird and Henry.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, March 6, 1862; 8x5; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, March 16, 1862; 11-1/2x8; Rathvon, S. S., (Simon Snyder), 1812-1891
    Lancaster, A.L.S. 2p. Mutilated. Concerning religious bans on the eating of swine.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, May 17, 1862; 8x5; Houghton, J. S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, May 22, 1862; 8x5; Rathvon, S. S., (Simon Snyder), 1812-1891
    Lancaster, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Concerning insects. Refers to Le Conte
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, June 4, 1862; 10x8; Houghton, J. S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p., end. Mutilated. Concerning the insects ruining the trees in Philadelphia.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Lancaster, Oct. 13, 1862; 9x5-1/2; Newton, Isaac
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Business.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Oct. 14, 1862; 8x5; Entomological Society of Philadelphia.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: E.T. Cresson. 1p. and end. Informs him of his election to membership in the society.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Lancaster, Oct. 20, 1862; 8x5; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Refers him to Cope at the academy for question on reptiles.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Oct. 24, 1862; 8x5; Entomological Society of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: E. T. Cresson. 2p. and end. Business. Entomology.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Oct. 29, 1862; 8x5; Cresson, E[zra] T[ownsend], 1838-
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Entomology.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Nov. 20, 1862; 8x5; Entomological Society of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: E. T. Cresson. 1p.and end. Business.
  - Letter to [Jacob Stauffer], Nov. 27, 1862; 9x5-1/2; Judd, Orange, 1822-1892
    New York, A.L.S. 2p., end. Mutilated. Concerning payment for articles.
  - Letter to J[acob] J.[sic] Stauffer, Dec. 26, 1862; 10x8; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    Germantown, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Dec. 27, 1862; 12x8; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning fishes.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, [1862]; 8x5; Wingate, John D.
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. Mutilated. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Jan. 12, 1863; 8x5; Entomological Society of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: E. T. Cresson. 1p. and end. Has sent certificate of membership to him and Rathvon.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Jan. 12, 1863; 8x5; Young, William S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and end. Business.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, March 22, 1863; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning fishes and lizards. Refers to Gill.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, April 28, 1863; 8x5; Ivison, Phinney & Co.
    New York, L. 1p. and end. Forwards publication by Gray.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, May 7, 1863; 8-1/2x5; Cresson, E. T. (Ezra Townsend), 1838-1926
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Concerning entomology. Refers To Say.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Sept. 22, 1863; 10x8; Houghton, J. S.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Sept. 24, 1863; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Haverford, A.L.S. 4p., end. Concerning fishes.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Dec. 29, 1863; 8x5; Wickersham, James Pyle, 1825-1893
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. and end. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Jan. 13, 1864; 8x5; Wickersham, James Pyle, 1825-1893
    A.L.S. 2p. and end. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, Feb. 1, 1864; 8x5; Beck, John
    A.L.S. 2p. and end.with sketches on end page. Mutilated. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, April 4, 1864; 7x4-1/2; Conyngham, Jasper Yeates, ca. 1810-ca. 1880
    Lancaster, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Business.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, April 6, 1864; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Concerning fishes.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, April 10, 1864; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning fishes.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, July 1, 1864; 10x7-1/2; Houghton, J. S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning entomology.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, July 6, 1864; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p., end. Mutilated. Concerning fishes.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, Oct. 24, 1864; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Haverford, A.L.S. 5p. Concerning fishes, Agassiz, and the Academy of Natural Sciences.
  - Letter to J. R. Sypher, January 25, 1865
    Senator Charles [ill.] regrets that he cannot honor invitation.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, April 21, 1865; 8x5; Houghton, J. S.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, April 29, 1865; 10x7-1/2; Houghton, J. S.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, May 23, 1865; 10x7-1/2; Houghton, J. S.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, May 25, 1865; 10x7-1/2; Houghton, J. S.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, June 29, 1865; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Haverford, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning fishes.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Lancaster, Oct. 13, 1865; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Haverford, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning fishes.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, Feb. 27, 1866; 8x5; Cresson, E. T. (Ezra Townsend), 1838-1926
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Business.
  - Letter to J. P. McCaskey, Lancaster, March 14, 1866; 10x8; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Mutilated. Will place the Linnean society of Lancaster on mailing list of the Smithsonian Institution.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, April 14, 1866; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Haverford, A.L.S. 4p., end. Concerning fishes and the academy of natural sciences.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, April 24, 1866; 8x5; Houghton, J. S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Mutilated. Concerning entomology.
  - Letter to J. P. McCaskey, May 9, 1866; 8x5; Benade, W. H.
    Pittsburgh, A.L.S. 3p. Thanks for being made a member of the Linnean Society. Concerning archaeology. Freeman Guide 438.
  - Letter to J. P. McCaskey, May 12, 1866; 8x5; Thurston, George
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for being made a mamber of the Linnean Society of Lancaster.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Lancaster, June 22, 1866; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    West Haverford, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning fishes.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, July 13, 1866; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Haverford, A.L.S. 2p., end Concerning fishes and entomology.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Aug. 19, 1866; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Haverford, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Concerning fishes and a dinosaur.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Aug. 30, 1866; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Lancaster, Aug. 30, 1866; 8x5; Foltz, J. M.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Sept. 16, 1866; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Haverford, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Concerning fishes.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Lancaster, Dec. 24, 1866; 8x5; Hoopes, Josiah, 1832-1904
    West Chester, A.L.S. 2p., end. Mutilated. Concerning entomology.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Dec. 28, 1866; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Feb. 18, 1867; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning snakes and fishes.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Feb. 25, 1867; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Loss, S. S.
    Philadelphia, L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Business.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, March 10, 1867; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Haverford, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Mutilated. Concerning snakes.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, March 11, 1867; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    A.L.S. 3p. and end. Concerning snakes and fossils.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, March 26, 1867; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Udderzook, Marshall J.
    Christiana, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Concerning a snake. Refers to Cope.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, July 29, 1867; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    A.L.S. 3p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning entomology and birds.
  - Note to [Jacob] Stauffer, Nov., 1868; 10x8; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    []. A.N.S. 1p. Mutilated. Concerning Riley's letter. On same sheet as letter from Riley to Meehan; Nov. 3, 1868.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Jan. 12, 1868; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    A.L.S. 2p., end. Mutilated. Concerning entomology.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, April 5, 1868; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, L.S. 2p. and end. Concerning fishes.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, May 20, 1868; 8x5; Greenwald, E. (Emanuel), 1811-1885
    Lancaster, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Thanks for being made a member of the Linnean Society of Lancaster.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, July 5, 1868; 8x5; Mann, Horace, 1796-1859
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Business.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Sept. 9, 1868; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brooks, Edward, 1831-
    Millersville, A.L.S. 2p., end. Mutilated. Business. Refers to the Linnean society of Lancaster.
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s Meehan, Nov. 3, 1868; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
    St. Louis, A.L.S. 1p., end. Mutilated. Concerning botany. On same sheet is note from Meehan to Stauffer; [Nov. 1868].
  - Letter to Jac[ob] Stauffer, Nov. 13, 1868; 10x8; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
    St. Louis, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning entomology.
  - Letter to Jac[ob] Stauffer, Dec. 6, 1868; 10x8; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Lancaster, April 5, 1869; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Portland Society of Natural History (Me.)
    Portland, L.S.(signature mutilated) 1p. Mutilated. Requests aid for cabinet of natural history.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, April 12, 1869; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Portland Society of Natural History (Me.)
    Portland, A.L.S. (signature mutilated) 2p. Mutilated. Concerning natural history. Refers to the Linnean Society.
    Unlocated 3/2011
  - Letter to Jac[ob] Stauffer, April 21, 1869; 8x5; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
    St. Louis, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to Jac[ob] Stauffer, Aug. 28, 1869; 10x8; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
    St. Louis, A.L.S. 2p. Mutilated. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Lancaster, Nov. 2, 1869; 10-1/2x8; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Will place him on the mailing list of the Smithsonian Institution.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Dec. 30, 1869; 8-1/2x5; Willett, Charles S.
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p.and end. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Lancaster, Jan. 12, 1870; 9x5-1/2; Glover, Townend, 1813-1883.
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Contains also sketches of fishes. Concerning entomology.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Lancaster, Jan. 25, 1870; 8x5; White, Henry Clay, b. 1848
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Mutilated. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Lancaster, Feb. 15, 1870; 8x5; White, Henry Clay, b. 1848
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Mutilated. Business.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Feb. 21, 1870; 7-1/2x5; Dickey, O. J.
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, May 5, 1870; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, L.S. 3p.and end. Concerning fishes and snakes.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, May 10, 1870; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Haddonfield, A.L.S. 2p. Mutilated. Concerning fishes.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, June 10, 1870; 7x4-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p.and end. Mutilated. Concerning fishes.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, June 25, 1870; 7x4-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, June 30, 1870; 8x5; Moore, Daniel D. T.
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. Mutilated. Business.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, July 8, 1870; 7x4-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Haddonfield, A.L.S. 2p.and end. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, July 29, 1870; 7x4-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Haddonfield, A.L.S. 4p.,end. Friendly letter. Concerning fishes.
  - Letter to [Jacob Stauffer], Nov. 30, 1870; 10x8; Moore, Charles
    New York, A.L.S.(signature mutilated) 1p. Mutilated. On reverse is sketch of a horse. Business.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, Jan. 3, 1871; 8x5; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
    St. Louis, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Jan. 27, 1871; 10x8; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
    St. Louis, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, Jan. 28, 1871; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Moore, Daniel D. T.
  - Letter to [Jacob Stauffer], April 3, 1871; 8x5; Porter, Thomas Conrad, 1822-1901
    Easton, A.L.S. 2p., end. Mutilated. Concerning mosses. Refers to Lesquereux and the Linnean Society.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, June 22, 1871; 7x4-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for invitation to visit the Linnean Society of Lancaster.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, Aug. 29, 1871; 8x5-1/2; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    Germantown, A.L.S. 1p. Mutilated. Concerning botany.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Nov. 21, 1871; 7x4-1/2; McCosh, James
    Princeton, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Dec. 6, 1871; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Bragdon, C. D.
    New York, A.L.S. 2p.,end. Mutilated. Business.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Dec. 21, 1871; 10x8; Riley, Charles V., (Charles Valentine), 1843-1895
    St. Louis, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning entomology. Refers to Rathvon.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, Dec. 25, 1871; 7x4-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Friendly letter. Concerning fossils.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, Feb. 10, 1872; 10x8; Hoopes, Josiah, 1832-1904
    West Chester, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Business.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Lancaster, July 19, 1872; 8x5; King, Ben
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Concerning Edward D. Cope.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Aug. 24, 1872; 8x5; Porter, Thomas Conrad, 1822-1901
    Easton, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Mutilated. Concerning botany. Refers to the Linnean Society.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Nov. 9, 1872; 8x5; Worth, S. G.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Concerning Cope.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, Dec. 4, 1872; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p., end. Mutilated. Concerning leeches, salamanders and fossils.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Lancaster, March 27, 1873; 9x6; Edge, Thomas J.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Mutilated. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Dec. 26, 1873; 8x5; Davenport, Geo. E. (George Edward), 1833-1907
    Boston, A.L.S. 3p.and end. Mutilated. Concerning botany.
  - Letter to Jacob Stauffer, Lancaster, Jan. 27, 1874; 5x5-1/2; Rathvon, S. S., (Simon Snyder), 1812-1891
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Mutilated. Concerning the Linnean Society.
  - Letter to [Jacob] Stauffer, Jan. 10, 1875; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Haddonfield, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning snakes and fishes.
  - Letter to J[acob] Stauffer, March 24, 1875; 8x5; Williamson, John, 1826-1885.